tywayne.com tywayne@gmail.com 405-808-5405

I am a designer and front-end developer with experience building responsive designs for everything from basic marketing websites to software used on hundreds of thousands of websites. I enjoy both the creative work that comes from designing a beautiful project with solid UI/UX, and the technical side of making it all actually work in a browser. In my free time, I enjoy spending time with my wife and son, as well as chasing after my retired racing greyhound, or drinking a nicely brewed pot of tea.

Experience

ITHEMES - LEAD FRONT-END DEVELOPER AND PRODUCT DESIGNER OCTOBER 2011 - PRESENT

iThemes is a software company providing tools and resources for freelancers and entrepreneurs who build/maintain websites on WordPress. As the lead front-end developer and designer I have a hand in almost every product iThemes creates.

My main responsibility has been iThemes Sync, a custom Software-as-a-Service application that provides remote management of multiple WordPress websites in a central location. I designed the original application, built out the front-end, and provide continued design/development of new features. The backend is built in PHP, uses Smarty for front-end templating, and relies heavily on JS for AJAX interactions on each screen.

I have also provided UI/UX design for BackupBuddy (a premium WordPress plugin used on over 500,000 sites), iThemes Security (WordPress plugin used on over 700,000 sites), and iThemes Exchange (an eCommerce WordPress plugin).

ELEMENT FUSION (NETSUITE) - WEB DESIGNER NOVEMBER 2010 - OCTOBER 2011

After becoming very familiar with LightCMS while working at Collision Media, I went to work for the company that built LightCMS. While there I designed and developed multiple websites for clients on the platform. I also designed and built free templates that were available to select when signing up for a LightCMS account.

COLLISION MEDIA - DESIGNER MAY 2009 - NOVEMBER 2010

Responsibilities included a spectrum of design work, for both print and web. Mainly focused around marketing materials for non-profit organizations and churches. I designed identity packages as well as other marketing collateral, and simple brocure websites on the LightCMS platform.

Education

SOUTHWESTERN OKLAHOMA STATE UNIVERSITY

(2008) B.A. Communication Arts - Speech Emphasis, Marketing Minor

Skillset

Adobe Photoshop
Adobe Illustrator
UI/UX Principles